instarem.com 2016-03-01

# INSTAREM PRIVACY POLICY

INSTAREM
PRIVACY
POLICY
      Feb 2015

CONTENTS
1. WHAT KINDS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION DO
   WE COLLECT AND HOLD?
2. WHY DO WE COLLECT, HOLD, USE AND
   DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION?
3. HOW DO WE COLLECT
   PERSONAL INFORMATION?
4. WHO DO WE DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL
   INFORMATION TO, AND WHY?
5. SECURITY OF INFORMATION COLLECTED
6. DO WE DISCLOSE PERSONAL
   INFORMATION OVERSEAS?
7. DO WE USE OR DISCLOSE PERSONAL
   INFORMATION FOR MARKETING?
8. ACCESS TO AND CORRECTION OF
   PERSONAL INFORMATION
9. RESOLVING YOUR PRIVACY CONCERNS AND
   COMPLAINTS - YOUR RIGHTS

PRIVACY POLICY
                                                            could contain credit information. Instarem may therefore
‘ INSTAREM              LIMITED
RESPECTS YOUR RIGHTS TO PRIVACY
                                         (INSTAREM)         collect information about you that it has obtained from
                                                            businesses that provide information about the credit
UNDER, AND IS BOUND BY, THE PRIVACY                         worthiness of individuals, including consumer credit
ACT 1988 (CTH) (ACT), THE AUSTRALIAN                        reports from a credit reporting body.
PRIVACY            PRINCIPLES            (AVAILABLE         Sometimes we collect personal information about you
ATWWW.OAIC.GOV.AU).                        INSTAREM         from other people
DEALS WITH PERSONAL INFORMATION
COLLECTED BY IT IN ACCORDANCE WITH                          HOW DO WE COLLECT PERSONAL
THIS PRIVACY POLICY (POLICY). WHEN                          INFORMATION?
USED IN THIS POLICY, “PERSONAL                              We collect most personal information directly from you
INFORMATION” HAS THE MEANING                                through the access and use of the Instarem website.
GIVEN IN THE ACT, BEING IN GENERAL                          Where you are a client of Instarem, Instarem may be
TERMS, INFORMATION OR OPINION                               subject to compliance with its obligations under the Act
ABOUT AN IDENTIFIED INDIVIDUAL, OR                          and may access third party electronic databases
AN INDIVIDUAL WHO IS REASONABLY                             necessary to assist it to identify you and such databases
IDENTIFIABLE.
                     ’                                      could contain credit information. Instarem may therefore
                                                            collect information about you that it has obtained from
This is a summary of our Privacy Policy.                    businesses that provide information about the credit
                                                            worthiness of individuals, including consumer credit
WHAT KINDS OF PERSONAL                                      reports from a credit reporting body.
INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND                               Sometimes we collect personal information about you
HOLD?                                                       from other people
When you apply for our products or services, we collect
information that is necessary to be able to provide you     WHO DO WE DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL
with those products or services. For instance, we may       INFORMATION TO, AND WHY?
ask for identification information such as your name,       We may share your personal information with other
address, driving license number and date of birth.          Instarem Group companies. Sometimes we may disclose
                                                            your personal information to organisations outside the
Instarem is required to collect certain personal            Instarem Group such as
information under the Anti-Money Laundering and
Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006, rules and other       i. to Instarem’s contractors or service providers for the
subordinate instruments (AML/CTF Laws).                     purposes of conducting its business and providing its
                                                            services or products to you, including web hosting
WHY DO WE COLLECT, HOLD, USE AND                            providers, IT systems administrators and payment
DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION?                              processors,
We collect most personal information directly from you      ii. to Instarem’s intermediary banks in order to process
through the access and use of the Instarem website.         certain transactions on your behalf, for example, by
Where you are a client of Instarem, Instarem may be         disclosing your name and address;
subject to compliance with its obligations under the Act    iii. to any partners, agents or intermediaries who are a
and may access third party electronic databases             necessary part of the provision of Instarem’s products
necessary to assist it to identify you and such databases   and services;
www.instarem.com                                          Instarem Pty Ltd ACN 601 384 025 AFSL 464627         PAGE 1

PRIVACY POLICY
iv. to international intermediaries to complete your            ‘Contact us’.
transactions;
v. to credit reporting bodies if you are a client of Instarem   RESOLVING YOUR PRIVACY CONCERNS
for the purpose of identifying you, in which case the           AND COMPLAINTS - YOUR RIGHTS
information will be limited to your identity particulars,       If you are concerned about how your personal
including your name, sex, address , date of birth and           information is being handled or if you would like to make
                                                                a complaint, please contact us on the details listed at
drivers licence number;
                                                                ‘Contact us’.
vi. to any government regulatory bodies that normally           If you are unhappy with our response, there are other
require it or may request it;                                   bodies you can go to.
                                                                The Financial Ombudsman Service (FOS) can consider
SECURITY OF INFORMATION COLLECTED                               most complaints about your credit information involving
We use a range of physical and electronic security              providers of financial services.
                                                                FOS can be contacted at:
measures to protect the security of the personal
                                                                Financial Ombudsman Service
information we hold. For example
                                                                GPO Box 3
• access to information systems is controlled through           Melbourne VIC 3001
identity and access management;                                 Phone: 1300 78 08 08
• employees are bound by internal information security          www.fos.org.au
policies and are required to keep information secure;           Under the Privacy Act you may complain to the Office of
• Data is held in highly secure servers                         the Australian Information Commissioner about the way
                                                                we handle your credit information.
DO WE DISCLOSE PERSONAL                                         The Commissioner can be contacted at:
INFORMATION OVERSEAS?                                           GPO Box 5218
We may disclose your personal information to recipients         Sydney NSW 2001
located outside Australia. These entities may include:          Phone: 1300 363 992
• Instarem Group companies                                      Email: enquiries@oaic.gov.au
• Instarem Group service providers; and                         www.oaic.gov.au
• International Intermediaries                                  Contact us
                                                                You can contact us by:
DO WE USE OR DISCLOSE PERSONAL                                  • writing to us at support@instarem.com
INFORMATION FOR MARKETING?                                      Our Privacy Officer can also be contacted in relation to
We will use your personal information to offer you              privacy concerns by writing to privacy@instarem.com
products and services that we believe may interest you.
We will not do this if you tell us not to.
Unless you tell us not to, we will disclose your personal
information to companies within the Instarem Group so
they can market their products and services to you.
ACCESS TO AND CORRECTION OF
PERSONAL INFORMATION
You can request access to the personal information we
hold about you. You can also ask for corrections to be
made. To do so, please contact us on the details listed at
www.instarem.com                                              Instarem Pty Ltd ACN 601 384 025 AFSL 464627         PAGE 2

THANK
YOU!
